Jordan Rector

Houston, TX · 281-382-0369 · rectorjordan94@gmail.com · GitHub · LinkedIn · Fortnite Creator

Full-stack software engineer & web developer with a diverse background in hospitality and game design. Passionate about solving complex problems with a knack for creative solutions. Dedicated to crafting user-friendly experiences that tackle modern challenges head-on. Actively pursuing ongoing education and skill development to stay ahead in an ever-evolving professional landscape.

SKILLS

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Express, Node.js, React, MongoDB, Mongoose, Photoshop, Canva, Figma, Slack, Zoom, Unreal Engine 5, UEFN, Microsoft Suite, Bootstrap, LiquidJS, AWS, Postgresql, Python, Django, Communication, Teamwork, Problem Solving, Empathy, Time-Management, Adaptability, Open-Mindedness

PROJECTS

<u>Centipede</u>, Sole Developer

Dec. 2022 - Dec. 2022

- Remake of the classic arcade game, playable directly in the browser
- Developed with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, & canvas
- Features keyboard & button inputs for player movement & projectiles, randomly generated environmental obstacles, level progression, player lives, game reset, & scoring

Everdell-Wiki, Sole Developer

Jan. 2023 - Jan. 2023

- Collaborative, full-stack wiki app made in the MVC system with authentication, authorization, & full CRUD on the app's main resource
- Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bootstrap, & LiquidJS

hoist{m}, Frontend Manager

Feb. 2023 - Feb. 2023

- Full-stack MERN app and Google Drive/Dropbox clone using AWS s3 cloud storage and multer middleware for file upload.
- Collaborative project built with two fellow software engineers, in which I acted as frontend manager but also contributed to a significant portion of the backend development as well
- Made with React, CSS, JavaScript, Express, Node.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, Axios, & Bootstrap

BLINK, Sole Developer

Mar. 2023 - Mar. 2023

- Full-stack Slack clone where users can create and join different channels and chat with other users in real-time.
- Built with the MERN stack and utilizing socket.io for bidirectional event-based communication between clients and server for chat functionality.
- Created with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Node.js, and socket.io

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive Fellow

Dec. 2022 - Mar. 2023

Remote

- Completed 500+ hours of expert-led instruction in JavaScript, HTML, and CSS, and Python. Including hands-on learning of Node.js, Django, Git, GitHub, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, Postgresql, and other industry leading technologies

Wooster's Garden Bartender/Assistant Manager

Jan. 2021 - Current Houston, TX

- Regularly served 500+ guests in a night
- Memorization and execution of 50+ house cocktails
- Weekly production of infusions & syrup
- Ordering, vendor relations, and inventory management of all beverage items

Brix Wine Cellars/Brixology Crafted Cocktails Beverage Director

Mar. 2017 - Aug. 2020 Houston, TX

- Researched current trends for beverage program development, regularly implemented and trained all bar staff on new processes, adhered to established quality & safety standards
- Created 50+ original cocktails, managed an inventory consisting of 1,000+ items
- Curated social media presence, managed events, implemented online ordering platforms, developed menu and responsible for photography and graphic design

EDUCATION

Software Engineering immersive

General Assembly

Web Developer Bootcamp

Udemy

Dec. 2022 - Mar.2023

Remote

Nov. 2021 - Jan. 2022

Remote